

///====== questions array===========//
var questions = [
    {
        id:"1",
        question: "Which of the following defines a measurement in inches?",
        answer: "in",
        options:[
            "in",
            "mm",
            "pc",
            "pt"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"2",
        question: "Which of the following property is used to set the color of a text?",
        answer:  "color",
        options:[
            "direction",
            "color",
            "word-spacing",
            "letter-spacing"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"3",
        question: "Which of the following property changes the width of top border?",
        answer: "border-top-width",
        options:[
            "border-bottom-width",
            "border-top-width",
            "border-left-width",
            "border-right-width"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"4",
        question: "What does HTML stands for?",
        answer: "Hypertext Markup Language",
        options:[
            "Hypertext Machine language.",
            "Hypertext mark language.",
            "Hypertext Markup Language",
            "Hightext machine language"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"5",
        question: "How is document type initialized in HTML5.?",
        answer: "<!DOCTYPE HTML>",
        options:[
            "</DOCTYPE HTML>",
            "</DOCTYPE>",
            "<!DOCTYPE HTML>",
            "</DOCTYPE html>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"6",
        question: "Which of the following HTML Elements is used for making any text bold ?",
        answer: "<b>",
        options:[
            "<p>",
            "<i>",
            "<li>",
            "<b>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"7",
        question: "Which of the following HTML element is used for creating an unordered list?",
        answer: "<ul>",
        options:[
            "<ui>",
            "<i>",
            "<em>",
            "<ul>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"8",
        question: "Which of the following characters indicate closing of a tag?",
        answer: "/",
        options:[
            ".",
            "/",
            ";",
            "!"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"9",
        question: "What is the font-size of the h1 heading tag?",
        answer: "2 em",
        options:[
            "3.5 em",
            "2.17 em",
            "2 em",
            "1.5 em"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"10",
        question: "Which of the following attributes is used to add link to any element?",
        answer: "href",
        options:[
            "link",
            "ref",
            "href",
            "newref"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"11",
        question: "What is the purpose of using div tags in HTML?",
        answer: "For creating different sections",
        options:[
            "For creating Different styles.",
            "For creating different sections",
            "For adding headings",
            "For adding titles"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"12",
        question: "Which of the following tags is used to make a portion of text italic in HTML?",
        answer: "<style= “i”>",
        options:[
            "<italic>",
            "<style= “i”>",
            "<i>",
            "<style=“italic”>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"13",
        question: "Which of the following attributes is used to open an hyperlink in new tab?",
        answer: "target",
        options:[
            "tab",
            "href",
            "target",
            "ref"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"14",
        question: "Which tag is used for creating a drop-down selection list?",
        answer: "<option>",
        options:[
            "<select>",
            "<option>",
            "<dropdown>",
            "<list>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"15",
        question: "Markup tags tell the web browser",
        answer: "How to display the page",
        options:[
            "How to organise the page",
            "How to display the page",
            "How to display message box on page",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"16",
        question: "www is based on which model?",
        answer: "Client-server",
        options:[
            "Local-server",
            "Client-server",
            "3-tier",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"17",
        question: "Which of the following selector selects the elements that are checked?",
        answer: ":checked",
        options:[
            "E ~ F",
            "::after",
            ":checked",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"18",
        question: "Which of the following selector selects an element that has no children?",
        answer: ":empty",
        options:[
            ":empty",
            ":nochild",
            ":inheritance",
            ":no-child"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"19",
        question: "By applying an ___________ a style can be applied to just a single tag.",
        answer: "id rule",
        options:[
            "class rule",
            "element rule",
            "id rule",
            "none of the mentioned",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"20",
        question: "Which of the following selectors selects siblings?",
        answer: "E, F, G",
        options:[
            "E.class",
            "E ~ F",
            "*",
            "E, F, G"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"21",
        question: "_______ property defines the space between cells in a table.",
        answer: "border-spacing",
        options:[
            "border",
            "border-spacing",
            "border-style",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"22",
        question: "Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?",
        answer: "<script>",
        options:[
            "<js>",
            "<scripting>",
            "<javascript>",
            "<script>"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"23",
        question: "What is the correct syntax for adding comments in JavaScript?",
        answer: "//This is a comment",
        options:[
            "<!–This is a comment–&gt",
            "//This is a comment",
            "–This is a comment",
            "**This is a comment**"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"24",
        question: "What is the JavaScript syntax for printing values in Console?",
        answer: "micro",
        options:[
            "print(5)",
            "console.log(5);",
            "console.print(5);",
            "print.console(5);"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"25",
        question: "JavaScript is a ________ Side Scripting Language.",
        answer: "Browser",
        options:[
            "Server",
            "ISP",
            "Browser",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
];








